{"1": {"question": "Mozart: What period is the initial development of chamber music linked to?", "correct": "Classical Period", "incorrect": ["Baroque Period", "Romantic Period", "Jazz Period", "The 80's"]}, "2": {"question": "Mozart: What feature separates the string quartet from Baroque forms?", "correct": "Basso continuo", "incorrect": ["It requires a violin", "Its music is better", "Cheaper", "Its instrumentation is different"]}, "3": {"question": "Mozart: When did the first string quartets appear?", "correct": "In the 1760's", "incorrect": ["Stone Age", "In the 1800's", "In the 1780's", "Jesus time, brah"]}, "4": {"question": "Mozart: Where did the first string quartets appear?", "correct": "South Germany, Austria, Bohemia", "incorrect": ["In ur mum's basement", "China", "Germany and Bolivia", "New Orleans"]}, "5": {"question": "Mozart: To which socioeconomic group did this music appeal?", "correct": "Enlightened' upper classes", "incorrect": ["Poor lower classes", "Hard-working American taxpayers", "Poor upper classes", "Rich homeless people"]}, "6": {"question": "Mozart: How many players are required and what kind of space is it played in?", "correct": "4 players in a small space", "incorrect": ["4 players in a large space", "3 players in a small space", "5 players in a large space", "The entire population of the Asian continent (approximately 4.5 billion)"]}, "7": {"question": "Mozart: Where were the quartets composed and when?", "correct": "In Vienna, between 1782 and 1785", "incorrect": ["In ur mum's basement", "In Italy between 1782 and 1785", "Nazi Germany", "Germany in the early 1800's"]}, "8": {"question": "Mozart: How many of the quartets were composed?", "correct": "6", "incorrect": ["5", "1", "4", "1,000,000,000,000"]}, "9": {"question": "Mozart: Who were the set of quartets dedicated to?", "correct": "Haydn", "incorrect": ["Bach", "Mozart", "Beethoven", "Jesus"]}, "10": {"question": "Mozart: To which work(s) were the works written in response to?", "correct": "Haydn's Op. 33 set", "incorrect": ["Mozart's Op. 10 set", "Beethoven's Op. 28 set", "Haydn's Op. 34 set", "Baby shark"]}, "11": {"question": "Mozart: What are the four movements in this String quartet K 387?", "correct": "Fast movement, Slow movement, Minuet and trio, Fast finale", "incorrect": ["Fast movement, even faster movement, even more faster movement, a movement that's so fast you didn't even realise it was playing until it ended", "Fast movement, Slow movement, Fast movement, Slow movement", "Fast movement, fast movement, slow movement, minuet and trio", "Slow movement, slower movment, fast finale, minuet and trio"]}, "12": {"question": "Mozart: What are the two main archetypes of a theme in the Classical style?", "correct": "Sentence and period", "incorrect": ["Sentence and full stop", "Sentence and response", "Dark mode and light mode", "Syncopation", "Archetypes don't exist, conspiracy confirmed"]}, "13": {"question": "Mozart: What comprises a 'sentence' theme?", "correct": "A 'presentation' phrase then a 'continuation and cadential' phrase", "incorrect": ["A theme that sentences.", "A continuation phrase then a presentation of the results", "A basic idea then a repetition of the basic ideas", "Some words and then a full stop at the end."]}, "14": {"question": "Mozart: What does a presentation phrase comprise of?", "correct": "A two bar basic idea which is either repeated or modified", "incorrect": ["An eight bar basic idea thats repeated again so its 16 so thats quick maths", "A two bar idea followed by another two bar idea", "A four bar idea which is repeated", "A song thats topping the charts"]}, "15": {"question": "Mozart: How many parts does the development have?", "correct": "4", "incorrect": ["3", "5", "6", "As many as there are points in my IQ (in that case, none)"]}, "16": {"question": "Mozart: What type of theme does the first four bars of the exposition suggest?", "correct": "Period-type theme", "incorrect": ["Sentence theme", "Yellow theme", "Halloween theme", "Cadential theme"]}, "17": {"question": "Mozart: Instead of returning to the initial basic idea at bars 5 and 6, what does the melody do?", "correct": "Fragmentary process like the 'continuation' of the sentence type", "incorrect": ["A process called photosynthesis", "The melody exposes the material from the development", "It finishes in an imperfect cadence", "It votes for Biden"]}, "18": {"question": "Mozart: What kind of theme does this become?", "correct": "A kind of 'hybrid' theme of the period and sentence themes", "incorrect": ["A triple theme", "A period theme", "A sentence theme", "It doesn't"]}, "19": {"question": "Mozart: How many additional bars are added to the standard eight-bar structure at bar 1?", "correct": "2", "incorrect": ["4", "8", "1", "262"]}, "20": {"question": "Mozart: What are the two cadences that occur at bar 8 and bar 10?", "correct": "Interrupted and Perfect", "incorrect": ["Interrupted and Plagal ", "Plagal and Perfect ", "Pianist", "Imperfect and Perfect"]}, "21": {"question": "Mozart: In which bar does the transition begin?", "correct": "Bar 11", "incorrect": ["Bar 18", "Bar 1", "Bar 9", "Bar Mitzvah"]}, "22": {"question": "Mozart: In which parts is the basic idea restated then imitated?", "correct": "Second violin then first violin", "incorrect": ["First violin then second violin", "Second violin then third violin", "First violin then the baritone saxophone", "Upper North Shore"]}, "23": {"question": "Mozart: To where does the piece modulate to by bar 16?", "correct": "Dominant", "incorrect": ["Subdominant", "Tonic", "Leading Note", "Alabama"]}, "24": {"question": "Mozart: Which key is bars 21-24 in, and what does this create?", "correct": "D major, creating a drawn-out imperfect cadence in dominant key", "incorrect": ["G major, creating a perfect cadence", "F flat major, creating disharmony amongst the music community", "E major, creating contrast to the previous section", "It is in the key of C chromatic scale because that is what everything is in (massive brain moment)"]}, "25": {"question": "Mozart: What does Mozart play tricks on?", "correct": "Expectations of Classical thematic conventions", "incorrect": ["His unicycle", "His own mind, he was delusional", "Expectations of Jazz people", "Everyone and everything and everyone"]}, "26": {"question": "Mozart: How many extra bars are added to the standard eight-bar structure commencing at bar 25?", "correct": "6", "incorrect": ["4", "2", "1", "26"]}, "27": {"question": "Mozart: What does the repitition of the basic idea a step lower from bar 25 at bar 27 suggest?", "correct": "A sentence-type theme", "incorrect": ["A period theme", "Mozart was loony ", "It doesn't suggest anything, stop being so suspicious", "The basic idea was repeated a step lower"]}, "28": {"question": "Mozart: At bar 29, what would usually follow the repition of the basic idea?", "correct": "Fragmentation and continuation", "incorrect": ["Repitition", "Syncopation", "The basic idea", "Sentence and period"]}, "29": {"question": "Mozart: What happens at bar 29 instead?", "correct": "A two bar contrasting idea with a weak imperfect cadence", "incorrect": ["A similar idea with a perfect cadence", "A contrasting idea with an imperfect cadence", "The basic idea followed by a plagal cadence", "The basic idea is repeated in a different key"]}, "30": {"question": "Mozart: Which bars are the first and second subordinate themes?", "correct": "First is 25, second is 39", "incorrect": ["First is 39, second is 49", "They happen simultaneously", "First is at bar 40, second at 50", "Yellow submarine"]}, "31": {"question": "Mozart: What is the name of the totality of subordinate themes?", "correct": "Subordinate theme group", "incorrect": ["Subordinate themes", "Ordinate Subtheme group", "Total of subordinate themes", "It is themes of subdorndasdlfk"]}, "32": {"question": "Mozart: How does the second subordinate theme differr from the first subordinate theme?", "correct": "It is less distinctive, consisting of more 'generic' passage work", "incorrect": ["It is more distinctive, as it includes the original material while experimenting with it", "It stays quite similar", "It comes after the first subordinate theme", "It is less distinctive, consisting of very repetitve phrases"]}, "33": {"question": "Mozart: Nearing the end of the exposition, there is a reptitive harmonic motion, mainly through which chords?", "correct": "IV-V-I", "incorrect": ["I-V-vi", "V-VI-I", "I-IV-V", "ii-V-I"]}, "34": {"question": "Mozart: What kind of cadence occurs at bar 47?", "correct": "Interrupted", "incorrect": ["Plagal", "Imperfect", "Perfect", "Cadence constructions"]}, "35": {"question": "Mozart: What closes the second subordinate theme and where?", "correct": "A harmonic progression towards a perfect cadence at bar 49", "incorrect": ["A harmonic progression towards an imperfect cadence at bar 49", "A chromatic progression towards a perfect cadence at bar 39", "A ii-V-I progression at bar 49", "A harmonic progression towards a perfect cadence at bar 49"]}, "36": {"question": "Mozart: How many bars at the end of the exposition are included in the 'closing section'?", "correct": "6", "incorrect": ["All of them", "8", "4", "2"]}, "37": {"question": "Mozart: What usually comprises a closing sections?", "correct": "A series of cadence-like gestures (codettas)", "incorrect": ["Notes", "References to the basic idea from the opening", "A series of perfect cadences", "Dramatic phrasing"]}, "38": {"question": "Mozart: What is presented in the case of this closing section at the end of the exposition?", "correct": "Cadence-like gestures (marked by a and b)", "incorrect": ["Notes", "Chords from the development section", "Nothing (ladies and gentlemen, introducing - drum roll please - Mozart the rebel)", "Conclusive phrasing"]}, "39": {"question": "Mozart: Who is Joe?", "correct": "Joe mama", "incorrect": ["Joe Biden", "Joseph Stalin", "Joe's sandwich bar", "Joe (musician)"]}, "40": {"question": "Mozart: Where is the logical place to close the exposition?", "correct": "Bar 53", "incorrect": ["Bar 50", "Bar 55", "When the exposition starts because nobody wants to listen to it", "China"]}, "41": {"question": "Mozart: What is presented at bar 53 in the case of this piece?", "correct": "Also a cadential formula, but something entirely new and distinctive", "incorrect": ["Not a cadential formula, something entirely new and distinctive", "A cadential formula, with a closing perfect cadence that is completely to be expected", "A cadential progression that happens at the end of every exposition", "Global warming"]}, "42": {"question": "Mozart: What makes bars 54 and 55 distinctive?", "correct": "Dotted rhythms and total homophony", "incorrect": ["It is so polyphonic that you decide to become breatharian", "The articulative phrasing", "The notes don't fit the chords"]}, "43": {"question": "Mozart: What bar does the development start?", "correct": "56", "incorrect": ["65", "70", "1", "62"]}, "44": {"question": "Mozart: Part 1 of the development contains how many phrases?", "correct": "3", "incorrect": ["2", "4", "8", "17"]}, "45": {"question": "Mozart: What is the structure of each phrase in part 1 of the development?", "correct": "Motif x followed by a newly composed extension", "incorrect": ["Motif x followed by motif y", "Complete random structure where nobody has any idea what is happening", "A motif that is repeated", "Motif a followed by motif b followed by motif c followed by motif d etc."]}, "46": {"question": "Mozart: The first phrase of part 1 of the development places the motif + extension in which part?", "correct": "1st Violin", "incorrect": ["Viola", "Cello", "Saxophone", "2nd Violin"]}, "47": {"question": "Mozart: The second phrase of part 1 of the development places the motif + extension in which part?", "correct": "2nd Violin", "incorrect": ["Viola", "Cello", "Saxophone", "1st Violin"]}, "48": {"question": "Mozart: The third phrase of part 1 of the development places the motif + extension in which part?", "correct": "Viola", "incorrect": ["1st Violin", "2nd Violin", "3rd Violin", "Cello"]}, "49": {"question": "Mozart: Could Mozart shred", "correct": "Probably not", "incorrect": ["Absolutely", "Without a doubt", "Definitely", "Mhm"]}, "50": {"question": "Mozart: What key is the development mainly in?", "correct": "D major", "incorrect": ["A major", "G major", "D minor ", "Circular Quay"]}, "51": {"question": "Mozart: The first phrase of part 1 of the development does what harmonically?", "correct": "Commences in D major and concludes in E minor", "incorrect": ["Stays in D major", "Cycle of fifths progression towards C major", "Commences in D major and ends in A major", "Provides an opportunity for a bass solo"]}, "52": {"question": "Mozart: The second phrase of part 1 of the development does what harmonically?", "correct": "Moves through a circle of fifths progression toward C major", "incorrect": ["Remains in C major", "Commences in D major then moves to E minor", "Nothing, everyone just goes quiet and stares at the floor", "It searches for resolution in the tonic"]}, "53": {"question": "Mozart: The third phrase of part 1 of the development does what harmonically?", "correct": "Remains in C major", "incorrect": ["Remains in D major", "Commences in C major then moves to A minor", "Cycle of fifths progression towards the tonic, D major", "Moves to the dominant key, A major"]}, "54": {"question": "Mozart: How can the harmonic nature of the music be described at the first part of the devleopment section?", "correct": "Flexible", "incorrect": ["Consistent", "Boring", "Unpredictable", "Repetitive"]}, "55": {"question": "Mozart: What does the viola complete its thematic entry (motif + extension) with in phrase 3 of part 1 of the development?", "correct": "An unaccompanied flourish, which is a further extension", "incorrect": ["A phrase that fits a perfect cadence", "A phrase that fits an imperfect cadence", "Fragments of the basic idea", "A dessert"]}, "56": {"question": "Mozart: The viola's solo passage in the third phrase of part 1 of the development creates a model that is used where?", "correct": "The sequence for the commencement of part 2 of the devleopment", "incorrect": ["The sequence for the end of part 1 of the development", "At the end of part 2 of the development", "At the end of the development", "In a showroom"]}, "57": {"question": "Mozart: Where and what size is the model created by the viola's solo passage in the third phrase of part 1 of the development?", "correct": "A two bar unit in bars 72-73, heard another three times in sequence", "incorrect": ["A two bar unit in bars 70-71, heard another three times in sequence", "A four bar unit in bars 72-75, heard again in sequence", "A four bar unit in bars 70-73, heard another three times in sequence", "A 2 minute long model that outlines the points that the team will debate"]}, "58": {"question": "Mozart: The sequence that the viola's model in the third phrase of part 1 of the development is  played over what?", "correct": "Unresolved dominant 7th chords on a chromatically rising bass line", "incorrect": ["A harmonic progression of ii-V-I that continues with a bass line", "Unresolved diminished 7th chords on a chromatically rising bass line", "Imperfect and interrupted cadences ", "The double bass parts"]}, "59": {"question": "Mozart: How does the second part of the development constrast to the first?", "correct": "The second establishes a sense of purpose in constrast to the more exploratory and hesitant first part", "incorrect": ["The second part is in a different mode as opposed to the first one", "The second part is more hesitant as opposed to the first which has a sense of purpose", "More expressive techniques are used as opposed to the first part which lacks interest and variety", "It doesn't happen"]}, "60": {"question": "Mozart: What is often thought of as the core of the development?", "correct": "The moment of decisiveness (sequencing techniques following a less clearly directed part)", "incorrect": ["The new theme being introduced", "A hard seed, similar to a peach", "The basic idea from the exposition being developed", "The movement into a different key that is not the dominant"]}, "61": {"question": "Mozart: At which bar does the sequencing finish in part 2 of the development?", "correct": "Bar 80", "incorrect": ["Bar 82", "Bar 78", "Bar 1", "Bar 92.5"]}, "62": {"question": "Mozart: What key does the sequencing in part 2 of the development finish in and the development remain in?", "correct": "E minor", "incorrect": ["G major", "C major", "A minor", "H diminished"]}, "63": {"question": "Mozart: Which bars in part 2 of the development confirm the key and dissipate the syncopation?", "correct": "80-81", "incorrect": ["81-82", "82-83", "1-170", "80-83"]}, "64": {"question": "Mozart: What begins at bar 82?", "correct": "A new thematic unit", "incorrect": ["A new era for the American people", "The closing section of the exposition", "A new motif ", "The development"]}, "65": {"question": "Mozart: What does the second thematic unit of part 2 of the development comprise?", "correct": "A two bar unit", "incorrect": ["A four bar unit", "An eight bar unit", "A sixteen bar unit", "A one bar unit"]}, "66": {"question": "Mozart: In which part does the second two bar unit in part 2 of the development occur and how many times?", "correct": "First violin twice", "incorrect": ["Second violin once", "Second violin twice", "First violin once", "Viola twice"]}, "67": {"question": "Mozart: From where do bars 86-89 draw material?", "correct": "Closing section of the exposition, in particular motifs b and c ", "incorrect": ["The beginning of the development section", "The beginning of the exposition, especially motif a", "One of Mozart's other works", "From a quarry"]}, "68": {"question": "Mozart: What does part 3 of the development commence with?", "correct": "A new sequence with a one bar model ", "incorrect": ["A new sequence with a two bar model", "A bang", "Material from the closing section of the exposition", "A sense of purpose"]}, "69": {"question": "Mozart: In what bar does part 3 of the development begin?", "correct": "Bar 90", "incorrect": ["Bar 82", "Bar 88", "Bar 102", "Bar 92"]}, "70": {"question": "Mozart: By how much higher is each sequence than the model at the beginning of part 3 of the developement?", "correct": "A perfect fourth", "incorrect": ["A perfect fifth", "An octave", "A tone", "Out of the audible spectrum"]}, "71": {"question": "Mozart: The first two sequences in part 3 of the development express what cadence type?", "correct": "V7-I", "incorrect": ["IV-I", "I-V7", "vi-vii", "All of the above"]}, "72": {"question": "Mozart: What happens at bars 92-93 instead of the expected V7-I?", "correct": "V7-VI", "incorrect": ["Viola", "V7-I", "I-V7", "Vi7-vi"]}, "73": {"question": "Mozart: What key does the new theme in part 3 of the development work towards (at bars 93-97)?", "correct": "D major", "incorrect": ["A major", "B minor ", "C major", "All of the above"]}, "74": {"question": "Mozart: The exposition's closing section is heard again at bars 97-100, but it is in which key?", "correct": "D major", "incorrect": ["D minor", "A major", "B minor", "E major"]}, "75": {"question": "Mozart: What is part 4 of the development usually called?", "correct": "Retransition", "incorrect": ["Transition", "Closing section ", "End bit", "The end of an old life but the beginning of a new one"]}, "76": {"question": "Mozart: What happens in part 4 of the development harmonically?", "correct": "The dominant harmony in the tonic key is introduced", "incorrect": ["The subordinate melody in the tonic key is introduced", "The subordinate themes are repeated in the harmonic parts", "The dominant harmony in the dominant key is introduced", "It has a solo"]}, "77": {"question": "Mozart: What two kinds of variation to the exposition can be expected in the recapitulation?", "correct": "Decorative and Structural", "incorrect": ["Structural and Exploratory", "Decorative and Festive", "Notational and Structural", "All of the above"]}, "78": {"question": "Mozart: What are decorative changes?", "correct": "Variations to expression; no material change", "incorrect": ["Variations to material; no expressional change", "Setting up a Christmas tree", "Any substantially new or altered material", "Ornamentations and trills added for interest"]}, "79": {"question": "Mozart: What are structural changes?", "correct": "Any substantially new or altered material", "incorrect": ["Changes to the layout of the section", "Different ideas replacing the old ones", "Variations to expression; no material change", "Like when a banana is genetically edited to become a pineapple"]}, "80": {"question": "Mozart: The plan of the recapitulation is fairly similar to the plan of the exposition, except for what key difference?", "correct": "Everything is now in the tonic", "incorrect": ["Everything is now in the dominant", "Everything is now in a minor key", "The structure of them are completely different", "Its at the end instead of the beginning"]}, "81": {"question": "Mozart: What and where is the only difference in the main theme in the recapitulation?", "correct": "At bar 116, additional one-bar unit presented", "incorrect": ["At bar 118, additional one-bar unit presented", "At bar 116, additional two-bar unit presented", "At bar 120, additional four-bar unit presented", "There is no difference"]}, "82": {"question": "Mozart: What is the main alteration in the transition of the recapitulation?", "correct": "A structural change at bar 123, which allows the rest of the transition to be in the tonic key", "incorrect": ["A decorative change at bar 123, which allows the rest of the transition to be in the tonic key", "yeetus to the foetus", "A structural change at bar 125, which allows the rest of the transition to be in the tonic key", "The key is changed, meaning that the listener is thrown off"]}, "83": {"question": "Mozart: Are there any surprises in the first subordinate theme in the recapitulation?", "correct": "No", "incorrect": ["Yes", "Maybe", "None of the above because there is no such thing as a subordinate theme", "Definitely possible but no because everything is not possibly definite"]}, "84": {"question": "Mozart: Are there any surprises in the second subordinate theme in the recapitulation?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["No", "Maybe", "None of the above because there is no such thing as a subordinate theme", "Definitely possible but possibly maybe because everything is not possibly definite"]}, "85": {"question": "Mozart: Does the closing section of the recapitulation differ from the closing section of the exposition and how?", "correct": "Yes, with some changes to octave reiger and two additional repeats of motive b", "incorrect": ["Yes, with some changes to the key and notation", "No it doesn't", "Yes, it contains different melodic ideas", "What's a closing section"]}, "86": {"question": "Schubert: What is the instrumentation of the piece?", "correct": "Voice and piano", "incorrect": ["Solo instrument and piano", "Orchestra", "String quartet", "Two pianos"]}, "87": {"question": "Schubert: What does Frühlingstraum mean?", "correct": "Spring dream", "incorrect": ["Winter dream", "Fruity Plum", "Violin", "Autumn dream"]}, "88": {"question": "Schubert: What kind of song is it?", "correct": "An art song", "incorrect": ["A pop song", "hell nah", "A sing song sang sung", "An instrumental song"]}, "89": {"question": "Schubert: What is D. 911", "correct": "Catalogue of his works", "incorrect": ["A random letter followed by a number", "Doomsday, 911 incident", "His 911th work", "A magazine catalogue"]}, "90": {"question": "Schubert: Who wrote the text for the work?", "correct": "Wilhelm Müller", "incorrect": ["J.K. Rowling", "Marcus Hildebrandt", "Leo", "Morenz Bittermann"]}, "91": {"question": "Schubert: What does Lied mean in German?", "correct": "Song", "incorrect": ["Piece", "Music", "Piano", "Past tense for 'lie'"]}, "92": {"question": "Schubert: How many songs are in the set called Winterreise?", "correct": "24", "incorrect": ["11", "16", "4", "911"]}, "93": {"question": "Schubert: In which place is Frühlingstraum in the set called Winterreise?", "correct": "11th", "incorrect": ["12th", "24th", "2nd", "DNF"]}, "94": {"question": "Schubert: What does Lied mean as a musical genre designation?", "correct": "A song set to German text", "incorrect": ["A song set to Italian text", "A piece of music with words", "Words with a piece of music", "A piece with words of music"]}, "95": {"question": "Schubert: How far back in time do Lied go?", "correct": "The Middle Ages", "incorrect": ["Jesus times", "The Renaissance", "The Dark Ages", "Prehistoric times (e.g. dinosaur)"]}, "96": {"question": "Schubert: In what time period did Lied develop to widespread recognition?", "correct": "The nineteenth century", "incorrect": ["Jesus times", "The eighteenth century", "10 minutes", "The seventeenth century"]}, "97": {"question": "Schubert: The devleopment of the Lied into widespread recognition had its roots where?", "correct": "The second half of the eighteenth century", "incorrect": ["The first half of the eighteenth century", "In the ground", "The second half of the seventeenth century", "The first half of the nineteenth century"]}, "98": {"question": "Schubert: What are the main reasons for the development of Lied into widespread recognition?", "correct": "The growth of German as a literary language, and how language can help social cohesion", "incorrect": ["The growth of Nazi Germany and Hitler's mo", "The growth of German as a literary language, and the development of Germany into a first-world nation", "The spread of European music across the world, and how language can help social cohesion", "Food from Germany becoming more popular around the world, and the love of their toilets"]}, "99": {"question": "Schubert: Who was at the forefront of the development of Lied into widespread recognition?", "correct": "Johann Wolfang von Goethe", "incorrect": ["Johann Sebastian Bach", "Heinrich Mitter", "Elmar Preiszner", "Ralf Reiter"]}, "100": {"question": "Schubert: What idea was developed by Johann Gottfried Herder?", "correct": "Language is the most powerful determinant of social cohesion", "incorrect": ["Music is the most powerful determinant of social cohesion", "The reason for the combination of music and language is that it sounds good", "That German food is tasty", "Language is the key tool of communication within a society"]}, "101": {"question": "What happened to Joe mama?", "correct": "They changed their last name to papa", "incorrect": ["They changed their last name to Biden", "Died in a hole R.I.P.", "Stopped practising saxophone so got spanked", "Joe"]}, "102": {"question": "Schubert: Whyy were peasants interested in Lied?", "correct": "The idea that Lied united everyone into one class", "incorrect": ["Lied gave them an opportunity to become rich performing it", "Lied let them understand what it was like to be in the upper class", "Peasants had a natural musical aptitude and therefore found it easier to learn and play", "They had nothing else to do"]}, "103": {"question": "Hello", "correct": "Goodbye", "incorrect": ["Die", "Why", "Hi", "Sigh"]}, "104": {"question": "Schubert: Why was much of the German poetry written in the early stages try to disconnect from the sophistication of the town/city?", "correct": "Town dominated by Italian opera, didn't want that style of music", "incorrect": ["Town dominated by Italian opera so they tried to rip it off outside of town", "The town was dominated by French opera, didn't want that style of music", "Town was dominated by German opera, but they didn't want that genre of music", "The sophistication of the urbanised areas did not suit the lifestyle of the peasants"]}, "105": {"question": "Schubert: The striving of German poetry during late 18th to early 19th Centuries toward oral folk traditions was for what purpose?", "correct": "People wanted an art that was unmediated by artificial formal conventions", "incorrect": ["People wanted music that had no connection to the music of the wealthy", "To revive folk music as it was very popular when it was around", "To remember and respect the ancestors of their music", "People wanted an art form that was not influenced by wealth or power"]}, "106": {"question": "Schubert: The urges for an art that was unmediated by artificial conventions (e.g. Italian opera) was amplified by what?", "correct": "The emerging Romantic movement", "incorrect": ["The emerging classical movement", "The emerging jazz movement", "Donald Trump's unwillingness to back down", "The emerging renaissance movement"]}, "107": {"question": "Schubert: What did the emerging Romantic movement emphasise?", "correct": "Unfettered expressions of feeling and emotion rather than the abstract appreciation of form", "incorrect": ["Undisturbed expressions of abstract appreciation of form rather than those of feeling and emotion", "The serious lack of aid provided by developed countries to developing countries", "Expressive techniques that were unique to the Romantic movement", "The emerging Romantic composers"]}, "108": {"question": "Schubert: What kind of feeling could this kind of music inspire in the individual?", "correct": "Feelings of the power of nature and awe and wonder", "incorrect": ["Feelings of the power of nature and resentment towards it", "Feelings of the weakness of nature and its dependence on humankind", "The awe and wonder inspired by a burrito", "How bad BTS is at making music (jk they don't make music)"]}, "109": {"question": "Schubert: What effect did the growing availability and popularity of the piano have on the development of the Romantic Lied?", "correct": "Led to the increasing numbers of German Lied being produced, due to presence in peoples' homes", "incorrect": ["Led to a serious shortage of piano teachers", "Led to a boom in the musical instrument manufacturing industry", "Led to the increasing numbers of German Lied being produced due to the lack of piano teachers", "Led to increasing numbers of home insurance claims due to the increased presence of pianos in peoples' homes"]}, "110": {"question": "Schubert: What caused composers to elevate the piano's role to support the text in Lied?", "correct": "The capacity for the piano to provide a level of inflection and subtlety not achievable on harpsichord", "incorrect": ["The capacity for the harpsichord to provide a level of inflection and subtelty not achievable on a piano", "The ability of the piano to play a variety of note durations and dynamics not achievable on a harpsichord", "The way the piano is able to play in a much larger range not achievable on harpsichord", "The ability to open the lid of the piano which is a cool function"]}, "111": {"question": "Schubert: Who was the first composer to realise the potential for a fusion of German poetic setting and sophisticated accompaniment", "correct": "Schubert", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Bach", "Finzi", "Xi Jinping"]}, "112": {"question": "Schubert: How many Lieder did Schubert compose in his career?", "correct": "Over 600", "incorrect": ["Over 800", "Under 100", "Under 600", "Over 1000"]}, "113": {"question": "Schubert: How are song cycles unified?", "correct": "All the songs are composed by the same composer, words from same poet, and have references to a particular theme or tell the same story", "incorrect": ["All the songs were composed by the same composer but the words were from different poets, and the dynamics were the same", "The songs were composed by different composers and the words are composed by different poets, and the story is different", "A binder, maybe some paper clips or staples", "By recurring motifs and ideas, also by using the same modes/keys"]}, "114": {"question": "Schubert: Who was the first composer to link individual Lieder together into unified collections?`", "correct": "Beethoven", "incorrect": ["Mozart", "Finzi", "Schubert", "Xi Jinping"]}, "115": {"question": "Schubert: What was Beethoven's first song cycle?", "correct": "An die ferne Geliebte Op. 98", "incorrect": ["Seufzer eines Ungeliebten - Gegenliebe WoO 118", "Liederkreis, Op. 39", "Dichterliebe", "The Dark Side of the Moon, Op. Pink Floyd"]}, "116": {"question": "Schubert: How many different approaches to a song cycle emerged?", "correct": "Two", "incorrect": ["Three", "Four", "One", "Ten"]}, "117": {"question": "Schubert: What was Beethoven's approach to song-cycles?", "correct": "Link the songs  by explicit recollection of musical motives between certain of the individual numbers", "incorrect": ["Link the songs by using a consistent range of dynamics and expressive techniques throughout the songs", "Link the songs through the use of musical ideas that remained the same throughout every song", "Present the songs as musically independent numbers and allow the narrative relationship to be more implicit", "Link the songs as musically reliant variables on the dominant seventh dimished chord of the tonic mode major key"]}, "118": {"question": "Schubert: What was the non-Beethoven approach to song-cycles?", "correct": "Present the songs as musically indepenedent numbers and to allow the narrative relationship to be more implicit", "incorrect": ["Link the songs by explicit recollection of musical motifs between certain of the individual numbers", "Link the songs through the use of musical ideas that remained the same throughout every song", "Present the songs as musically dependent numbers and allow the narrative relationship to be more implicit", "Link the songs as musically reliant variables on the dominant seventh dimished chord of the tonic mode major key"]}, "119": {"question": "Schubert: Which approach to song cycles was favoured by Schubert?", "correct": "The non-Beethoven one", "incorrect": ["The Beethoven one", "Both of them, because Franz likes variety", "Neither, because he brought about a third style that was his own and more obscure", "The Mozart one"]}, "120": {"question": "Schubert: When was Winterreise composed?", "correct": "1828", "incorrect": ["1928", "1826", "1905", "2020"]}, "121": {"question": "Schubert: Did Wilhelm Müller consider the poems as a cycle?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["No", "Maybe", "Probably", "Why not"]}, "122": {"question": "Schubert: In which perspective is the poem told from?", "correct": "First person", "incorrect": ["Second person", "Third person", "Fourth person", "Patient zero"]}, "123": {"question": "Schubert: How is the poet introduced in the set of poems?", "correct": "Leaving a village, passing the gate of his lost love he won in spring but has now lost", "incorrect": ["Leaving a village, passing the bakery at which he always used to buy bread from", "Entering a village, passing the gate of his lost love he won in spring but has not lost", "Leaving a village, passing his home where many memories were created", "Entering a village, smelling the delicious smells of baked bread and the pretty sights"]}, "124": {"question": "Schubert: In which sense is the poet on a journey?", "correct": "Physical and psychological", "incorrect": ["Physical and spiritual", "Spiritual and psychological", "Environmental and psychological", "Biological and psychological"]}, "125": {"question": "Schubert: What is an idea in the text that Müller constantly returns to?", "correct": "Constrast between illusion and reality", "incorrect": ["Contrast between Spring and Winter", "Contrast between walking and sitting", "Contrast between dreams and nightmares", "Contast between love and loneliness"]}, "126": {"question": "Schubert: What kind of attitude does the poet have?", "correct": "He is an outcast who will wander in solitude and never know companionship", "incorrect": ["He is highly likeable and will always have the companionship and love from others", "He is an outcast who will wander in companionship and love", "He is an extrovert who will wander in solitude and never know companionship", "He is an outcast who has many friends and his highly likebale"]}, "127": {"question": "Schubert: How is the higher awareness on the part of the poet expressed?", "correct": "He refers to the dreams of others and he knows the cold reality that awaits everyone", "incorrect": ["He refers to the dreams of higher beings and knows the cold reality that awaits everyone", "He refers to the dreams of others and he knows the pleasant reality that awaits everyone", "He refers to his own dreams and can see the future that awaits everyone", "The poet is able to see the cold reality that awaits everyone through his own dreams"]}, "128": {"question": "Schubert: What kind of rhyme scheme does Frühlingstraum have?", "correct": "abcabc", "incorrect": ["aabaac", "ababab", "abcdab", "aabbabababaaabbabababbabababbaababbabababababbababbab"]}, "129": {"question": "Schubert: What is the poet trying to promote in the text?", "correct": "A folk-like simplicity and artlessness", "incorrect": ["A folk-like complexity and artfulness", "The simplicity of the text", "A city-like complexity and thoughtfulness", "A city-like simpleness and artlessness"]}, "130": {"question": "Schubert: In some songs in the set Winterreise, the poet dreams himself, and awakens to a harsh reality. Is this the case in Frühlingstraum?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["Maybe", "I don't know, you tell me", "Most likely", "It is possible"]}, "131": {"question": "Schubert: How many quatrains does Frühlingstraum contain?", "correct": "6", "incorrect": ["8", "4", "2", "1"]}, "132": {"question": "Schubert: Each line in the poem comprises a loose what?", "correct": "Iambic trimeter", "incorrect": ["Iambic pentameter", "Grip on reality", "Iambic dimeter", "Iambic tetrameter"]}, "133": {"question": "Schubert: How can the poetic meter throughout the poem be described?", "correct": "Simple and consistent", "incorrect": ["Complex and irregular", "Complex and unpredictable", "Simple yet unpredictable", "Complex and consistent"]}, "134": {"question": "Schubert: How are the lines grouped?", "correct": "In pairs", "incorrect": ["In threes", "In fours", "In groups of ten thouSAND MILLION BILLION TRILLION GAZILLION", "Individually"]}, "135": {"question": "Schubert: How many metric feet are there in each line?", "correct": "Three", "incorrect": ["Two", "Four", "Seventeen", "Eleven thousand, nine hundred and eighty-four point three"]}, "136": {"question": "Schubert: What do the metric feet in most cases consist of?", "correct": "iambs (unstressed-stressed)", "incorrect": ["amphibrach (unstressed-stressed-unstressed)", "pyrrhic (unstressed-unstressed)", "dactyl (stressed-unstressed-unstressed)", "anapest (unstressed-unstressed-stressed)"]}, "137": {"question": "Schubert: In the first line of each pair, the final foot is what?", "correct": "amphibrach (unstressed-stressed-unstressed)", "incorrect": ["iambs (unstressed-stressed)", "pyrrhic (unstressed-unstressed)", "dactyl (stressed-unstressed-unstressed)", "anapest (unstressed-unstressed-stressed)"]}, "138": {"question": "What renders the metre loose rather than strict?", "correct": "Short additional syllables", "incorrect": ["Long additional syllables", "Medium-lenght additional syllables", "A shortage of syllables in some places", "A surplus of unnecessary syllables"]}, "139": {"question": "Schubert: Does the two-line metric preocess apply throughout the entire verse?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["No", "Maybe", "Probably NOT", "Huh"]}, "140": {"question": "Schubert: What are melismas?", "correct": "A group of notes sung to one syllable", "incorrect": ["A group of syllables placed on one note", "A group of notes sung on a group of syllables", "A group of notes sung on two syllables", "A syllable sung on a note"]}, "141": {"question": "Schubert: What does syllabic mean?", "correct": "One syllable per note", "incorrect": ["Two sylllables per note", "Three syllables per note", "Two notes per syllable", "One syllable per three notes"]}, "142": {"question": "Schubert: What do the quatrains marked A (1 and 4) symbolise?", "correct": "Spring, birds and flowers, blossoming love", "incorrect": ["A quatrain", "Cold reality of WInter, harsh calls of birds", "Yearning to return to dream state, despair that is all illusion", "The harsh reality of the seasonal cycle"]}, "143": {"question": "Schubert: What do the quatrains marked B (2 and 5) symbolise?", "correct": "Cold reality of Winter, harsh calls of birds", "incorrect": ["Spring, birds and flowers, blossoming love", "A quatrain", "Yearning to return to dream state, despair that is all illusion", "The harsh reality of the seasonal cycle"]}, "144": {"question": "Schubert: What do the quatrains marked C (3 and 6) symbolise?", "correct": "Yearning to return to dream state, despair that all is illusion", "incorrect": ["Spring, birds and flowers, blossoming love", "Cold reality of Winter, harsh calls of birds", "A quatrain", "The harsh reality of the seasonal cycle"]}, "145": {"question": "Schubert: How many times does the poem cycle through the dream-reality-longing (ABC)?", "correct": "2", "incorrect": ["3", "1", "4", "So many times you're gonna lose count :)"]}, "146": {"question": "Schubert: What bars is Section A?", "correct": "1-14", "incorrect": ["15-26", "2-15", "26-44", "1-16"]}, "147": {"question": "Schubert: What bars is Section B?", "correct": "15-26", "incorrect": ["13-25", "44-43", "15-28", "1-14"]}, "148": {"question": "Schubert: What bars is Section C?", "correct": "27-44", "incorrect": ["15-26", "1-14", "25-44", "27-45"]}, "149": {"question": "Schubert: How does Schubert delineate the contrasts between the different sections?", "correct": "Changes of key/mode, tempo, style, metre", "incorrect": ["Changes of key/mode, dynamics, style, texture", "Change of dynamics and tempo but not expressive techniques", "Expressive techniques, dynamics, key/mode, tempo", "Style, mode, metre, dynamics"]}, "150": {"question": "Schubert: What do major modes represent in this song?", "correct": "Dreaming, spring, warmth, love", "incorrect": ["Reality, winter, coldness, loneliness", "Reality, summer, heat, companionship", "Dreaming, winter, warmth, loneliness", "Spring, coldness, loneliness, love"]}, "151": {"question": "Schubert: What do minor modes represent in this song?", "correct": "Reality, winter, coldness, loneliness", "incorrect": ["Dreaming, spring, warmth, love", "Reality, summer, heat, companionship", "Dreaming, winter, warmth, loneliness", "Spring, coldness, loneliness, love"]}, "152": {"question": "Schubert: Which section comes closest to adopting a direct, folk song-like style?", "correct": "Section A", "incorrect": ["Section B", "Section C ", "Section D", "Sections A and B"]}, "153": {"question": "Schubert: The material in section A is almost entirely...", "correct": "Diatonic", "incorrect": ["Chromatic", "Minor", "Gone", "Changed"]}, "154": {"question": "Schubert: The material in section A is cast in how many simple phrases?", "correct": "2", "incorrect": ["4", "6", "8", "1"]}, "155": {"question": "Schubert: What does etwas bewegt mean?", "correct": "With some movement", "incorrect": ["tgeweb sawte", "With patience", "With movement", "Slightly faster"]}, "156": {"question": "Schubert: How does the piano accompaniment foreshadow the singer's line in Section A?", "correct": "A brief four-bar introduction", "incorrect": ["A brief two-bar introduction", "A brief one-bar introduction", "A brief six-bar introduction", "A brief eighteen-bar introduction"]}, "157": {"question": "Schubert: What is siciliana?", "correct": "A slow musical style with lilting rhythms resembling a slow jig", "incorrect": ["A type of pizza", "A fast musical style with syncopated rhythms resembling a rondo", "A slow musical style with even rhythms resembling a waltz", "A fast musical style that has irregular rhythms resembling a six year old learning the piano"]}, "158": {"question": "Schubert: What kinds of themes are siciliana rhythms usually associated with?", "correct": "Nature and simple bucolic life", "incorrect": ["Buildings and complicated city life", "Nature and complex bucolic life", "Margherita, meat lovers, Hawaiian, pepperoni", "Simple country life and farms with cows"]}, "159": {"question": "Schubert: Where can a simple period be detected in Section A?", "correct": "Antecedent (bars 5-8) and consequent (bars 9-14)", "incorrect": ["Consequent (bars 5-8) and antecedent (bars 9-14)", "From bars 4-15", "Antecedent (bars 9-14) and consequent (bars 15-21)", "Antecedent (bars 6-9) and consequent (bars 10-15)"]}, "160": {"question": "Schubert: How does Section B contrast to Section A?", "correct": "Tempo increase, key change, mode becomes minor, accompaniment more staccato", "incorrect": ["Key change, mode becomes major, accompaniment more legato, tempo decrease", "Tempo increase, key change, mode becomes major, accompaniment more staccato", "Tempo decrase, key change, mode becomes minor, accompaniment more legato", "Tempo increase, key change, key becomes minor, accompaniment more staccato"]}, "161": {"question": "Schubert: What is sustained in the piano part by a tonic pedal in section B?", "correct": "A low tremolo", "incorrect": ["A high tremolo", "Basso continuo", "Slash chords", "An inappropriate accomapniment"]}, "162": {"question": "Schubert: What do the triplet figures marked x in section B act as?", "correct": "Jolts that destablise dream equilibrium", "incorrect": ["Jolts that reinforce the dream equilibrium", "Jolts that make the listener pee their pants", "Jolts that destablise the Winter reality", "Lead-ins to the next bars"]}, "163": {"question": "Schubert: What does schnell mean?", "correct": "Fast", "incorrect": ["Slow", "Walking", "Medium", "Speeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeed"]}, "164": {"question": "Schubert: What are augmented 6th chords?", "correct": "Chromatic chords which resolve to the dominant or sometimes the tonic", "incorrect": ["Chromatic chords which resolve to the tonic or sometimes the dominant", "The 6th is augmented (duh)", "Diatonic chords which resolve to the dominant or sometimes the tonic", "Diatonic chords which resolve to the tonic or sometimes the dominant"]}, "165": {"question": "Schubert: How are augmented 6th chords constructed?", "correct": "On the minor 6th degree of the scale and always include a note an augmented 6th above that", "incorrect": ["On the major 6th degree of the scale and always include a note an augmented 6th above that", "Intervals of minor 6ths piled on top of each other", "On the minor 6th degree of the scale and always include a note an augmented 2nd above that", "On the major 6th degree of hte scale and always include a note an augmented 2nd above that"]}, "166": {"question": "Schubert: The triplet figures marked x in section B involve inversions of what chord?", "correct": "The French augmented 6th chord", "incorrect": ["The German augmented 6th chord", "The Italian augmented 6th chord", "The French augmented 2nd chord", "The French suspended 6th chord"]}, "167": {"question": "Schubert: What is the Neopolitan 6th in bar 23?", "correct": "A supertonic triad constrcuted on the lowered 2nd degree", "incorrect": ["A supertonic triad constructed on the lowered 6th degree", "A supertonic triad constructed on the 5th degree", "A supertonic fourth constructed on the 5th degree of the 6th mode of the dominant 7th chord", "The 6th flavour of Neopolitan ice-cream"]}, "168": {"question": "Schubert: Does chromatic writing continue over the tonic pedal in bars 22-26?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["No", "Maybe", "Possibly", "Probably"]}, "169": {"question": "Schubert: What feeling is created by the rapid modulation, chromatic harmony, minor-mode colouring and angular accompaniment in Section B?", "correct": "A powerful sense of disturbance, disorientation and distress - waking up from a dream", "incorrect": ["A powerful sense of reassurance, sleepiness and calmness - like falling asleep", "A powerful sense of disturbance, disorientation and distress - playing a note during a rest in an orchestra", "A powerful sense of disturbance, disorientation and distress - waking up from a dreamless sleep", "A powerful sense of reassurance, sleepiness and calmness - like eating chocolate"]}, "170": {"question": "Schubert: What does langsam mean?", "correct": "Slow", "incorrect": ["Fast", "Medium", "Turtle", "Speeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeed"]}, "171": {"question": "Schubert: What meter does Section C introduce?", "correct": "Simple duple", "incorrect": ["Simple triple", "Simple quadruple", "Compound duple", "Compound triple"]}, "172": {"question": "Schubert: What helps to set up a sense of stillness in section C after the agitation from section B?", "correct": "A new accompaniment pattern that remains quite constant", "incorrect": ["A new accompaniment pattern that varies a lot", "A reused accompaniment pattern that remains quite constant", "A new accompaniment that is constant in some parts and different in others", "An old accompaniment pattern that was drawn from a different song"]}, "173": {"question": "Schubert: The first two lines of text in Section C appear with a return to what key?", "correct": "The tonic major", "incorrect": ["The tonic minor", "The relative minor", "The dominant major", "The subdominant major"]}, "174": {"question": "Schubert: The first two lines in Section C are repeated, but what happens to the expected strong perfect cadence at bar 36?", "correct": "It is withheld", "incorrect": ["It is played as expected", "It is played and then repeated", "It is withheld and played two bars later", "It is played as unexpected, because they read the sheet music upside down"]}, "175": {"question": "Schubert: The arrival of the tonic in the bass is delayed until the final cadence in Section C, but what has changed regarding the mode?", "correct": "The mode is now minor", "incorrect": ["The mode is now major", "The mode is now diminished", "The mode is now dominant7", "The mode is now dark mode (iOS 14 feature)"]}, "176": {"question": "Schubert: How can the closure of Section C be described?", "correct": "Soaked with a feeling of loss and despair", "incorrect": ["Soaked with maple syrup like a pancake", "Soaked with a feeling of happiness and completion", "Soaked with a feeling of resentment and anger", "Epic"]}, "177": {"question": "Finzi: What kind of song is this?", "correct": "An English art song", "incorrect": ["A Lied", "A pop song", "An instrumental song", "A British art song"]}, "178": {"question": "Finzi: How far back does the genre English art song go?", "correct": "Late sixteenth to early seventeenth centuries", "incorrect": ["Late seventeenth to early eighteenth centuries", "Late sixteenth to early eighteenth centuries", "Late fifteenth to early sixteenth centuries", "Back in my day"]}, "179": {"question": "Finzi: Lute songs by which composers are notable from the late sixteenth to early seventeenth centuries?", "correct": "John Dowland and Thomas Campion", "incorrect": ["John Dowland and Henry Purcell", "Ralph Vaughan Williams and Henry Purcell", "Michael Jackson and Thomas Campion", "John Dowland and William Walton"]}, "180": {"question": "Finzi: Whose works marked a high point in seventeenth century English music across all genres?", "correct": "Henry Purcell", "incorrect": ["Ralph Vaughan Williams", "Thomas Campion", "Arnold Bax", "Barack Obama"]}, "181": {"question": "Finzi: How did foreign influences come to dominate the musical landscape in England?", "correct": "The importation of Italian opera and in the works of Handel", "incorrect": ["Uncontrolled immigration", "Work opportunities attracting foreigners to England", "Serious self-esteem issues on the part of English composers (most of which fell into a deep depression)", "Their music was more appealing to audiences in England"]}, "182": {"question": "Finzi: The solo songs in England were dominantly developing where?", "correct": "From outside of England", "incorrect": ["In England", "Oceania", "Asia", "The Americas"]}, "183": {"question": "Finzi: The German tradition of the Lied was a large influence on the English art song. Which composers were part of that genre?", "correct": "Franz Schubert, Robert Schumann, Felix Mendelssohn, Johannes Brahms", "incorrect": ["Robert Schumman, Johannes Brahms, Johann Sebastian Bach, Franz Schubert", "Felix Mendehlssohn, Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, Johann Wolfgang Beethoven, Robert Schumann", "Franz Schubert, Roberto Schumann, Felix Mendelssohn, Johann's Bras", "Franz Schubert, Felix Mendelssohn, Johannes Brahms, William Shakespeare"]}, "184": {"question": "Finzi: What factors led to a period termed by some as the 'English musical Renaissance'?", "correct": "A growing sense of national awareness amongst English musicians, supported by a folk-song revival movement", "incorrect": ["A growing sense of national identity and confidence amongst musicians in England", "An increase in English composers in England at the time creating more music", "Foreign composers claiming to be English immigrating to England and composing masterpieces", "A growing sense of national awareness that encouraged people to write less music"]}, "185": {"question": "Finzi: What kinds of music were rediscovered in the 'English musical Renaissance'?", "correct": " 'Pre-Handelian' English music (court music) and British folk music", "incorrect": ["Jazz music, especially the elevator variety", "British folk music and renaissance music", "Renaissance music and 'Pre-Handelian' English music (court music)", "Pre-Bachian' English music and British folk music"]}, "186": {"question": "Finzi: Examples of twentieth century composers that were beneficiaries of the re-emergence of English music after foreign domination:", "correct": "Ralph Vaughan Williams, John Ireland, Arnold Bax, William Walton, Benjamin Britten", "incorrect": ["John Ireland, Benjamin Britten, Franz Schubert, Mark Walton, Arnold Bax", "William Walton, Ralph Vaughan Williams, Henry Purcell, Benjamin Britten, Arnold Bax", "Ralph Vaughan Williams, John Coltrane, Arnold Bax, Benjamin Britten, Miles Davis", "Ralph Vaughan Williams, John England, Arnold Bax, William Waton, Benjamin Britain"]}, "187": {"question": "Finzi: Examples of important English poets whose texts were set to music include:", "correct": "Shakespeare, Milton, Wordsworth, Coleridge, Hardy", "incorrect": ["Shakespeare, Dickens, Coleridge, Hardy, Wordsworth", "Keats, Milton, Shakespeare, Donne, Wordsworth", "Blake, Wordsworth, Hardy, Keats, Shakespeare", "John Lennon, Paul McCartney, Ringo Starr, George Harrison"]}, "188": {"question": "Finzi: What instrumentation is an art song comprised of?", "correct": "Solo voice and instrumental accompaniment", "incorrect": ["String orchestra and soloist", "Solo voice", "Solo instrument and instrumental accompaniment", "A chamber choir with a string quartet"]}, "189": {"question": "Finzi: How many short cycles of songs did Finzi compose?", "correct": "At least 8", "incorrect": ["8", "At least 24", "10", "16"]}, "190": {"question": "Finzi: From which English poet is Finzi's Let us garlands bring's text from?", "correct": "Shakespeare", "incorrect": ["Coleridge", "Hardy", "Milhouse", "Wordsworth"]}, "191": {"question": "Finzi: Which of Shakespeare's plays is O mistress mine from?", "correct": "Twelfth Night", "incorrect": ["Macbeth", "Romeo and Juliet", "A Midsummer Night's Dream", "Hamlet"]}, "192": {"question": "Finzi: How many six-line stanzas (sextains) are there in the text?", "correct": "2", "incorrect": ["4", "6", "17.3", "8"]}, "193": {"question": "Finzi: What kind of rhyme scheme do the sextains have?", "correct": "aabccb", "incorrect": ["abacad", "x", "ababab", "abcabc"]}, "194": {"question": "Finzi: How is the form of the song best described?", "correct": "Semi-strophic", "incorrect": ["Strophic", "Through-composed", "Sonata form", "Binary form"]}, "195": {"question": "Finzi: What happens to the cadence at the end of each stanza?", "correct": "It is elided with the commencement of the next piano section", "incorrect": ["It is replaced with a sequence that leads to the commencement of the next piano section", "It is an imperfect cadence which leads nicely to the next section", "It is repeated except changed so it becomes a 'second go'", "The performer forgets about it because they have a mental blank and can't remember how to play their instrument"]}, "196": {"question": "What is a strophic song?", "correct": "Each stanza is set to the same music", "incorrect": ["No substantial repitition of music for each stanza", "A song without words", "A song with a very repetitive melody", "A song with a very repetitive harmony"]}, "197": {"question": "What is a through-composed song?", "correct": "No substantial repitition of music for each stanza", "incorrect": ["Each stanza is set to the same music", "A song without words", "A very thoroughly composed piece of music", "A song that has little to no repitition in it"]}, "198": {"question": "What is a semi-strophic song?", "correct": "Between strophic and through-composed, bit of the same music but also different in each stanza", "incorrect": ["A shorter strophic song", "A song with motifs and ideas that seem to match each other but are not the same", "A song with a repetitive melody that sometimes introduces new ideas", "A song that has verses that are the same as each other"]}, "199": {"question": "Where would the music be the same usually in a semi-strophic song?", "correct": "At the beginning of each stanza, being the most logical way to express identity", "incorrect": ["At the end of each stanza, being the best way to finish", "In the middle of each stanza because that is where the listener feels secure and understands the music", "At the beginning of the first stanza and the end of the second stanza", "At the end of the first stanza and the beginning of the second stanza"]}, "200": {"question": "Finzi: Which other composers have used this same text from Twelfth Night?", "correct": "Thomas Morley, Sullivan, Vaughan Williams, Charles Villers Stanford, Margaret Sutherland", "incorrect": ["Thomas Morley, Charles Dickens, Vaughan Williams, Margaret Sutherland", "Donald Trump, Vaughan Williams, Charles Villers Stanford, Sullivan, Thomas Morley", "Vaughan Williams, Shakespeare, Sullivan, Thomas Morley, Rudy Giuliani, Margaret Sutherland", "Purcell, Sullivan, Margaret Sutherland, Finzi, Thomas Morley"]}, "201": {"question": "Finzi: What key is O mistress mine in?", "correct": "Eb major", "incorrect": ["Bb major", "E major", "C minor", "Db major"]}, "202": {"question": "Finzi: Does O mistress mine ever modulate to another key?", "correct": "No", "incorrect": ["Yes", "Yes, to all 7 billion of them", "Nothing is impossible if you put your mind to it", "Definitely"]}, "203": {"question": "Finzi: How can the mood throughout most of the song be described?", "correct": "Light-hearted and jaunty", "incorrect": ["Dysphoric and delusional", "Anxious and irritable", "Cheerful and bright", "Melancholic and reflective"]}, "204": {"question": "Finzi: O mistress mine is mostly diatonic except for where?", "correct": "The final bars of each stanza where modal mixture is introduced", "incorrect": ["The opening bars of each stanza where the ideas are being introduced", "The middle of each stanza", "The bridges between the stanzas", "China because they banned the import of diatonic"]}, "205": {"question": "Finzi: Where does the mood change to become more reflective?", "correct": "At the end of each stanza with the modal mixture", "incorrect": ["At the beginning of each stanza", "At the beginning and the end of each stanza", "When it nears the end of its life", "In the middle of each stanza to add an element of surprise"]}, "206": {"question": "Finzi: What does the right hand primarily consist of?", "correct": "A free, two-part texture with occasional thickening", "incorrect": ["A free, three-part texture with occasional thinning", "A free flowing melody that occasionally thickens", "A restricted, two-part texture with occasional thickening", "Five fingers and a palm"]}, "207": {"question": "Finzi: What does the left hand primarily consist of?", "correct": "A staccato 'vamping' accompaniment", "incorrect": ["A staccato unpredictable accompaniment", "Long sustained notes from the chords", "A walking bass line", "A free flowing countermelody"]}, "208": {"question": "Finzi: What is a consistent feature present in the left hand accompaniment?", "correct": "A downward stepping motion from the second beat of the bar to the first beat of next bar", "incorrect": ["An upward stepping motion from the second beat of the bar to the first beat of the next bar", "A downward stepping motion from the first to the second beat of the bar", "Dominant tenths", "An upward stepping motion from the first to the second beat of the bar"]}, "209": {"question": "Finzi: How do the interlude and hte postlude compare to the introduction?", "correct": "They are quite similar", "incorrect": ["They substantially differ as they share no common music", "They are identical", "They are not related to each other in any way", "They are much shorter, but make up for it in dynamics"]}, "210": {"question": "Finzi: Are the musical material from the vocal line and the piano part dependent on each other?", "correct": "No they are relatively independent", "incorrect": ["Yes because they constantly imitate each other", "Yes due to how the parts interlock and play together", "No but they do share a lot of the same ideas, so actually yes", "Yes because they are both in a sticky financial situation due to the Coronavirus pandemic"]}, "211": {"question": "Finzi: What type of text setting is the text?", "correct": "Syllabic", "incorrect": ["Neumatic", "Melismatic", "Problematic", "Dolichocephalic"]}, "212": {"question": "Finzi: What is accountable for the subtle rhythm changes from stanza to stanza?", "correct": "Natural declamation", "incorrect": ["Rubato", "Natural tempo variation", "Natural emphasisation", "The incapable musician not being able to tap their foot"]}, "213": {"question": "Finzi: How do the first lines of each stanza compare rhythmically?", "correct": "Different in their natural speech rhythms and have a different number of syllables", "incorrect": ["They are the same", "They share some rhythmic groupings", "Different number of syllables but similar speech rhythms", "Different in their natural speech rhythms but same number of syllables"]}, "214": {"question": "Finzi: How does the piano accompaniment for the first lines of each stanza compare?", "correct": "It is identical", "incorrect": ["They are in different keys", "They are at different tempos", "They are similar with a few note changes", "The piano isn't playing at that part, get pranked Laugh Out LOUD"]}, "215": {"question": "Finzi: Does the highly flexible, natural text setting remain consistent throughout the song?", "correct": "Yes", "incorrect": ["No", "Maybe", "Possibly", "Naaaaaaaaaaah"]}, "216": {"question": "Finzi: At what points in the stanzas are the piano accompaniment and the melody similar?", "correct": "At the beginning and nearing the end", "incorrect": ["In the middle of both stanzas", "In the final line of both stanzas", "At the beginning of both stanzas", "Nowhere, because its a circle"]}, "217": {"question": "Finzi: Where is the only instance of direct imitation between the voice and the piano found?", "correct": "At the very final line in each stanza", "incorrect": ["The first line of each stanza", "The middle of the second stanza", "At the end of the song", "The beginning of the final stanza"]}, "218": {"question": "Finzi: What changes occur in the final two lines in each stanza?", "correct": "Harmony shifts to parallel minor, accompaniment texture changes, pace slows, dramatic dynamic contrast", "incorrect": ["Harmony shifts to parallel minor, pace quickens, overall texture becomes more dense and dynamics increase", "Harmony shifts up a major fifth, pace slows, accompaniment texture changes, dynamic contrast", "Pace quickens, accompaniment texture thins, pace slows, dynamics dramatically softer", "Nothing is changed here"]}}